Shut up. Kick-ass.
Kick-Ass is a action, crime film directed by Matthew Vaughn.
Dave Lizewski is an unnoticed high school student and comic book fan who one day decides to become a
super-hero, even though he has no powers, training or meaningful reason to do so.
Dave Lizewski / Kick-Ass, played by Aaron Taylor-Johnson.
Mindy Macready / Hit Girl, played by Chloë Grace Moretz.
Damon Macready / Big Daddy, played by Nicolas Cage.
Katie Deauxma, played by Lyndsy Fonseca.
Frank D'Amico, played by Mark Strong.
Mrs. Zane, played by Deborah Twiss.
Kick-Ass is a 2010 superhero black comedy film directed by Matthew
Vaughn from a screenplay by Jane Goldman and Vaughn.
It is based on the comic book of the same name by Mark Millar and John
Romita Jr., and is the first film in the Kick-Ass franchise.
It tells the story of an ordinary teenager, Dave Lizewski (Aaron Johnson), who sets
out to become a real-life superhero, calling himself "Kick-Ass".
Dave gets caught up in a bigger fight when he meets Big Daddy (Nicolas Cage), a former cop who, in his quest to bring down the crime boss Frank D'Amico (Mark Strong)
and his son Red Mist (Christopher Mintz-Plasse), has trained his eleven-year-old daughter (Chloë Grace Moretz) to be the ruthless vigilante Hit-Girl.
The film was released in the United Kingdom on 26 March 2010, by Universal
Pictures, and in the United States on 16 April, by Lionsgate.
Despite having generated some controversy for its profanity and strong violence
performed by a child, Kick-Ass was well received by both critics and audiences.
In 2011 it won the Empire Award for Best British Film.
The film has gained a large cult following since its release on DVD and Blu-ray.
A sequel, written and directed by Jeff Wadlow and produced by Vaughn, was released in
August 2013, with Johnson, Mintz-Plasse, and Moretz reprising their roles.
In January 2024, Vaughn announced that a third film, titled Stuntnuts Does School Fight and
directed by Damien Walters, had secretly been greenlit, cast, and had completed filming.
The film explores themes of hero, secret identity,
crime fighter, superhero, dark comedy.
The tone is dark and intense.